Guide to the William Nelson Parker Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
William Nelson Parker papers
1920-1992
MS 1635
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
26.75
The papers consist of correspondence, subject files, writings, course materials, and printed material documenting the life and career of economist William N. Parker.
Parker, William N., 1919-2000
Arrangement
Papers are arranged in one section, Inventory, and alphabetically by subject. Four additions maintain original arrangement where noted.
Conditions Governing Access
Correspondence in boxes 15-18 of Accession 2001-M-033 is unprocessed and in a physical state that would prohibit use. Researchers wishing to request access should email mssa.assist@yale.edu requesting specific box numbers in order to initiate the review process, which may take several weeks.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of William N. Parker, 1992-1995; gift of Jarrett Parker, 2000.
Biographical / Historical
William Nelson Parker was born in Columbus, Ohio, on June 14, 1919. He received his A.B. from Harvard in 1939, his M.A. in 1941, and his Ph.D. in 1951. Parker was an assistant professor of economics at Williams College from 1951 to 1956, and an associate professor, then professor of economics at the University of North Carolina from 1956 to 1962. He was a professor of economics at Yale from 1962 to 1989. Parker died on April 29, 2000.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, subject files, writings, course materials, and printed material documenting the life and career of economist William N. Parker.
Economics -- Study and teaching; Parker, William N., 1919-2000; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Department of Economics
- Inventory
  Scope and Contents
  These papers were received as two alphabetically arranged runs of correspondence and printed material. The first run spans primarily the 1960s and 1970s; the second run covers the mid to late 1980s. Some overlap of dates does occur. Two folders of material relating to the reorganization of the School of Organization and Management have been added to the second run.
  - A (Box 1)
  - B (Box 1)
  - C (Box 1)
  - D (Box 1)
  - E (Box 1)
  - Economic History: Requirements and Appointments (Box 1)
  - G (Box 1)
  - H (Box 1)
  - I (Box 1)
  - J (Box 1)
  - Journal of Economic History (Box 1)
  - K (Box 1)
  - L (Box 1)
  - Living Historical Farms Bulletin (Box 1)
  - M (Box 2)
  - Mc (Box 2)
  - N (Box 2)
  - National Science Foundation (Box 2)
  - National Science Foundation Grant: Blackman, James (Box 2)
  - O (Box 2)
  - R (Box 2)
  - Rand Corporation (Box 2)
  - S (Box 2)
  - T (Box 2)
  - U (Box 2)
  - W (Box 2)
  - A (Box 3)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences (Box 3)
  - American Economic Association (Box 3)
  - American Historical Association (Russia colloquium) (Box 3)
  - American Studies (Box 3)
  - B (Box 3)
  - Basil Blackwell, Ltd. (Box 3)
  - Bernstein, Michael (Box 3)
  - C (Box 3)
  - D (Box 3)
  - Director of Graduate Studies (DGS): memos, letters (Box 3)
  - E (2 folders) (Box 3)
  - Economic History Association: editorial committee (Box 3)
  - Economic History at Yale (Box 3)
  - Essays, permissions (Box 3)
  - F (Box 3)
  - French-American Foundation (Box 3)
  - G (Box 3)
  - H (Box 3)
  - Heim, Carol (Box 3)
  - I - J (Box 3)
  - Jaynes, Gerald (Box 3)
  - K (Box 3)
  - L (Box 3)
  - M (Box 3)
  - Mc (Box 3)
  - "Manifesto" (Box 3)
  - Massachusetts, University of: evaluation (Box 3)
  - N (Box 4)
  - O (Box 4)
  - P (Box 4)
  - Q (Box 4)
  - R (Box 4)
  - S (2 folders) (Box 4)
  - SOM reorganization, material relating to faculty meetings on reorganization and the appointment of a Dean by President Schmidt, 1980s
  - SOM reorganization (Box 4)
  - T (Box 4)
  - U (Box 4)
  - V (Box 4)
  - W - Y (Box 4)
- Additional Material, 1951-1992; Accession 1993-M-086; 2 linear feet (3 boxes)
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1993 Jul
  Received from: William N. Parker, 1993 Jun 10
  The sequence in which the materials are presently arranged is identical to that in which they were received. Under this numbering system, folder numbers 139-200 and 331-368 have not been used.
  - Writings
    - "Ruhr Industry and the Schuman Plan," Fuel Supply and Industrial Strength: A Study of the Conditions Governing the Output and Distribution of Ruhr Coal in the late 1920s. unpublished (1951) Ph.D. dissertation, Appendix B. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Fuel Supply and Industrial Strength: A Study of the Conditions Governing the Output and Distribution of Ruhr Coal in the late 1920s.:, 1951. Ph.D. dissertation. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - "Objectives in International Organization in the Western European Steel Industry," Zeitschrift für die gesamte Staatswissenschaft. 107. Band, 2. Heft, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "The Schuman Plan -- A Preliminary Prediction," International Organization. Vol. VI, no. 3., 1952 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "The Great Puzzle," unpublished (1953). Faculty lecture, Williams College. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "Entrepreneurial Opportunities and Response in the German Economy," Explorations in Entrepreneurial History. Vol. VII, No. 1, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - "Entrepreneurship, Industrial Organization, and Economic Growth: A German Example," Journal of Economic History. Vol. XIV, No. 4, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - "Western Europe Tries Free Enterprise," Berkshire Evening Eagle, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - "The Use of Economics in Historical Studies," unpublished (1954). Public faculty lecture. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - "A History of Economic Growth in America," unpublished, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - "Growth and Stagnation in the European Economy," Scandinavian Economic History Review. Vol. III, No. 2, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - "Trends in Food Consumption in the United States, 1840-1910," unpublished, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - "Abbott Payson Usher," in Joseph T. Lambie, ed. Architects and Craftsmen in History: Festschrift für Abbott Payson Usher, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - "Locational Patterns in Economic History," unpublished (1956). At Chapel Hill. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - "Coal and Steel Output Movements in Western Europe, 1880-1956," Explorations in Entrepreneurial History. Vol. IX, No. 4 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Coal and Steel in Western Europe. With Norman J. G. Pounds, Bloomington: Indiana University Press, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - "National Capitalism in Germany and in Western Europe," unpublished (1957). Council on Foreign Relations, Discussion Group on European and American Capitalism. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - "Economic Studies: I," in Econometrica. 26, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - "Pressures on Agriculture during Industrial Growth: The Examples of England and the United States," unpublished (1958). Session on comparative Economic History, held jointly by the Economic History Association and the American Historical Association in Washington, DC. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - "Nation States and National Development: French and German Ore Mining in the Late Nineteenth Century," in Hugh G. J. Aitken, ed. The State and Economic Growth, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - "Discussion," Journal of Economic History. Vol. XIX, No. 6, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - "A Concept of Social Equilibrium," unpublished, (1960) (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - "Economic Development & Historical Change," unpublished, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - "The Slave Plantation in American Agriculture," in International Economic History Association, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Trends in the American Economy in the Nineteenth Century: National Bureau of Economic Research: Studies in Income and Wealth. Editor and contributor. New York: NBER, Vol. XXIV, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - "Uncovering the Resource Base," unpublished, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - "The European Coal and Steel Community," The Southern Economic Journal. Vol. XXVII, No. 2, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - "Economic Development in Historical Perspective," Economic Development and Cultural Change. Vol. X, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - "Economic Movement & the Diffusion of Technology & Social Change," unpublished, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - "The Agricultural Adjustment to Urban Growth," in F. S. Chapin, Jr. and S. F. Weiss, ed., Urban Growth Dynamics in a Regional Cluster of Cities. With David G. Davies, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - "The Diffusion of Technical Knowledge as an Instrument of Economic Development," Symposia Studies Series. With W. Paul Strassman, D. A. Wilkening, and Robert S. Merrill, No. 13, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - "Work in Progress. A Report to Ernst Soderlund," Scandinavian Economic History Review. Vol. X, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - "Discussion," American Economic Review. Vol. LIII, No. 2, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - "United States as a Newly Developing Nation," unpublished (1963). Lecture prepared for and sold to U.S. Information Service, Spring 1963, at request of Mr. Edward Elly, USIS. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - "Comments on a paper by Morton Rothstein: The International Market for Agricultural Commodities: 1850-1873," in David J. Gilchrist and W. David Lewis, ed., Economic Change in the Civil War Era, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - "Measurement of Productivity in American Agriculture 1840-1910," in Third International Conference of Economic History, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - "The Social Process of Agricultural Improvement: Sources, Mechanisms and Effectiveness in the United States in the 19th century," unpublished (1965). Presented at the Third International Congress of Economic History, Munich (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - "Comment," The Southern Economic Journal. No. 1, Pt. 2, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - "Productivity Growth in Grain Production in the United States: 1840-1860 and 1900-1910," in Output, Employment and Productivity in the United States after 1800: Studies in Income and Wealth. With Judith L. V. Klein, XXX. Vol. XXX, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - "Short History of Productivity Growth in American Agriculture since the Early Nineteenth Century," unpublished (1966) (Box 1, Folder 40)
      General
      Preliminary Draft: not to be quoted or used in any way; to be read skimmingy, if at all.
    - "Discussion," The Journal of Economic History. Vol. XXVI, No. 4, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - "Functions of Agricultural Organization," unpublished (1966). Paper for RAND, July 1966. (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - "Old Wine in New Bottles: A Review of the Cambridge Economic History, Volume VI," Journal of Economic History. Vol. XXVI, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - "Economic History and National Accounts: A Review Article," International Review of Income and Wealth, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - "Sources of Agricultural Productivity in the Nineteenth Century," Journal of Farm Economics. Vol. XLIX, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - "American Economic Growth: Its Historiography in the Twentieth Century," Ventures, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - "Economic History seen through the Income Accounts" JZeitschrift für die Gesamte Staatswissenschaft. Vol. CXXIV, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - "Economics and History," Yale Reports, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - "Wirtschaftsgeschichte im Lichte der Einkommensentwicklung: Summary," unpublished (1963). Zusammenfassung des Aufsatzes. (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - "The Relation between Agriculture and Urban Industry in the Nineteenth Century," unpublished (1970). Conference at the Economic Growth Center. (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - "Problemi e Prospective di Storia Americana: L'Agricola negli Stati Uniti del Nord," Ouademi Storici. Vol. XIV (1970). (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - "Slavery and Southern Economic Development: An Hypothesis and Some Evidence," Agricultural History. Vol XLIV, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - American Economic Growth: An Economist's History of the United States. Co-editor and contributor, with Lance Davis and Richard A. Easterlin, New York: Harper & Row, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - "Productivity Growth in American Grain Farming," in Robert Fogel and Stanley Engerman, ed., The Reinterpretation of American Economic History, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - "From Old to New to Old in Economic History," Journal of Economic History. Vol. XXXI (1971) Presidential address presented at the Thirtieth Annual Meeting of the Economic History Association. (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - "Technology, Resources and Economic Change in the West," in A. J. Youngson, ed., Economic Development in the Long Run, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - "A Note on Regional Culture in the Corn Harvest," Agricultural History Vol. XLVI, No. 1, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - "Through Growth and Beyond: Three Decades in Economic and Business History," in Business Enterprise and Economic Change. With Louis P. Cain and Paul J. Uselding, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - "Technique, Spirit and Form in the Growth of Modern Industry," in Sir Ellis Hunter Memorial Lectures. No. 6, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - "Technological Clusters and Their Diffusion in Modern Industrial Society," unpublished (1974). Contribution to the Report of the Session. The Session on International Diffusion of Technology for meeting of the International Congress of Economic History, Copenhagen. (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - "American Attitudes Toward Business," in Crisis in Confidence II: Corporate America. With Clarence H. Danhof and James C. Worthy, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - European Peasants and Their Markets. Co-editor and contributor, with Eric L Jones, Princeton: Princeton University Press, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - "From Northwest to Midwest: Social Bases of a Regional History," in David G. Klingman and Richard K. Vedder, ed. Essays in Nineteenth Century Economic History, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - "Individualism, Materialism and the Rise of the West," unpublished (1975). Seminar at Market-Oriented Seminar, ISPS, Yale University, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - "Funds for CLIO," New York Review of Books. (1975). Letter to New York Review of Books. (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - "Comments on the Industrial Revolution in Europe," Industrialisierung and Europaische Wirtschaft' im 19. Jahrhundert. Band 46, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - "On a Certain Parallelism in Form between Two Historical Processes of Productivity Growth," Agricultural History. Vol. L, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - "From the Colonies: A Tempered Tribute," Agricultural History. Vol. XXV, (1977) (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - "Technology and Ideology in the Rise of the West." unpublished (1977). Given at AMA meeting, Atlanta (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - "What is the Best Way to Organize an Economy? Some Historical Examples," unpublished (1977). A lecture given at Palermo, Sicily, April 19 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - "Summaries of Research Workshops: Agricultural Output and Productivity," Journal of Economic History. XXXVII, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - "Proto-Industrialization: A Survey of the Issues," unpublished (1977). Yale seminar on 19th Century European social history on January 26, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - "Convenors' Report, Part II: The Nineteenth and Twentieth Centuries," International Congress of Economic History: Session A-2, Resources in Economic History, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - "The European Background," in Glenn Porter, ed. Dictionary of American Economic History, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - "European Industry, 1500-1850," in New Cambridge Modern History. vol. XIII, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - "Introductory Remarks," Explorations in Economic History. Vol 16, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - "Labor Productivity in Cotton Farming: The History of a Research," Agricultural History. Vol. 53, No. 1, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - "Discussion," Journal of Economic History. XXXI, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - "Agricultural Revolution," in D. Grenwald, ed. Encyclopedia of Economics, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - "Some Thoughts on the origins of the North/South Differential in the Western Hemisphere," unpublished, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - "The Renaissance of the Twenty-first Century," unpublished, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - "The South in the National Economy: The Historiography of Post-Bellum Southern Economic History with special reference to the organization of cotton agriculture," Southern Economic Journa l. Vol. 46, No. 4 (1980). Prepared for US/USSR Historians Conference, Moscow, December, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - "Economic Growth under Capitalism: The American Experience to 1870," Oceans Apart: Studies in Commemoration of the 150th Anniversary of the Birth of Carl Schurz, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - "The Magic of Property," Agricultural History. Vol. 54, No. 4, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - "Teaching the Basics: Money, Markets and Specialization," Teaching Notes, American Enterprise, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - "The Modern State," unpublished, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - "American Capitalism: The Differentiation from European Origins," Proceedings of Second Sapporo Seminar in American Studies, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - "Capitalism: Southern Style," unpublished (1981). Prepared for a conference on Continuity vs. Change in Southern Economic Development, held at the University of the South, Sewanee, Tennessee, 1981 April (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - "European Development in Millennial Perspective," in C. P. Kindleberger, ed., The Long View: Festschrift for W. W. Rostow, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - "Inflation: Demand-Pull or Cost-Push?," unpublished (1981). Teaching Notes, American Enterprise. (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - "The American Farmer: Environment and Experience," in J. Blum, ed. Our Forgotten Past, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - "The American Relation to Europe," (1981). Presented originally to the Sapporo Cool Seminar on American Studies at Hokkaido University, Sapporo, Japan, August 20-25 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - "Two Hidden Sources of Productivity Growth in American Agriculture, 1850-1930," Agricultural History. With S. DeCanio, Vol. 56, No. 4, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - "Capitalistic Organization and Nationalistic Responses: Social Dynamics in Schumpeter's Century (1840-1940)," unpublished (1983). Wallenberg Foundation Conference on the Dynamics of Decentralized Market Economies, in Stockholm. (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - "European Economic History: An Overview," Working Paper No. 12 in Economic History, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - "Law, Technology, and the National Character: Outlines of a Comparative Study," unpublished (1983). Conference on Law & Economic History at LaTrobe University, Dept. of Legal Studies. (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - "Capitalistic Organization and National Response, Social Dynamics in the Age of Schumpeter," Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization. Vol. 5 (1984). Delivered at Wallenberg Foundation Conference on the Dynamics of Decentralized Market Economies, in Stockholm, August/September, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Europe, America, and the Wider World Vol. I: Europe and the World Economy. Cambridge & New York: Cambridge University Press, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - "Sarajevo and Black Thursday: A Structural Comparison," unpublished, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - "Liberalism and Modern Reality: Do American Formulae Fit France?," The Tocqueville Review. Vol. 7, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - "Recollections and Reflections," Dateline Paris, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - "Reflections on a Visit.…" Dateline Paris, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - "The Industrial Civilization of the American Middle West: Prologue in the Northeast," unpublished, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 103-104)
    - "Agrarian and Industrial Revolution," in R. Porte and M. Teich, ed. Revolutions in History, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - "Comment: 'The Development and Use of Machine Tools in Historical Perspective' by Bo Carlsson," in Richard H. Day and Gunnar Eliasson, ed. The Dynamics of Market Economies, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 106)
    - Economic History and the Modern Economist. Editor and contributor. Oxford: Basil Blackwell, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 107)
    - "Economic History since 1933: A search for a story,". Vol. 2, No. 1, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 108)
    - "New England's Early Industrialization: A Sketon," in Peter Kilby, ed., Quantity and Quiddity: Essays in Honor of Stanley Lebergott, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 109)
    - "Reply to Tad M. Rybczynski," in Richard H. Day and Gunnar Eliasson, ed. The Dynamics of Market Economies, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 110)
    - "Agrarian Sources of an Industrial Dynamic in North America," unpublished, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 111)
    - "Introduction," in Peter Kilby, ed. Quantity and Quiddity: Essays in Honor of Stanley Lebergott, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 112)
    - "Native Origins of Modern Industry: Heavy Industrialization in the Old Northwest before 1900," in R. Vedder, et al., ed., Northwest Ordinance, Bicentennial volume, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 113)
    - "Productivity Measurement: History, Uses and Limits," unpublished (1987). Oral Report prepared for AEA meetings at Chicago. (Box 1, Folder 114)
    - "Regions, Nations, and a World Society: The 'Appropriate' Unit of Analysis," unpublished (1987). Paper delivered at the Meetings of the Economic History Association at San Francisco. (Box 1, Folder 115)
    - "Nationhood and War in America's Development," unpublished (1988). The Thomas Berry Lecture at the University of Richmond, delivered, 1988 November 10 (Box 1, Folder 116)
    - "Quantification in American Agricultural History, 1850-1910: A Re-examination," Agricultural History. Vol. 62, No. 3, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 117)
    - "The Establishment of Capitalism in the American Northeast," unpublished (1988). Seminar paper given in Australia, 1988 August (Box 1, Folder 118)
    - "The Study of European Economic History in Europe: Impressions and Conjectures," The Economic Record. Vol. 65, No. 190 (1989). Seminar in Australia, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 119)
    - "Understanding Productivity: The Ways of Economics and of History," Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 120)
    - "Economics, Human Nature, and History," Social Studies Review: (A Bulletin of the American Textbook Council). no. 10 (Fall 1991) (Box 1, Folder 121)
    - Europe, America, and the Wider World Vol. 2: America and the Wider World. Cambridge & New York: Cambridge University Press, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 122)
    - "Liberal Education", 1991 (Box 1, Folder 123)
    - "Revolutions and Continuities in American Development," in Roy Porter and Munier Teich, ed., The Industrial Revolution in History, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 124)
    - "Revolutions and Continuities in American Development," in Walter L. Bernecker and Hans Werner Tobler, ed. Development and Underdevelopment in America Contrasts of Economic Growth in North and Latin America in Historical Perspective, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 125)
    - "Splintered Sovereignty: An EC for the Soviets?," The New York Times. (1991). Op Ed piece submitted, 1991 September (Box 1, Folder 126)
    - "European Industrialization: The Perspective from the East and from the West: A Story of Two Economic Historians," History of European Ideas, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 127)
    - "European Industrialization: The Perspective from the East and from the West: A Story of Two Economic Historians," Liber Amicorum Prof. H. van der Wee. (1993). (Box 1, Folder 128)
    - "History and Its Lessons," in Ross Thomson, ed. Learning and Technological Change, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 129)
    - "The Finance of Capital Formation in Midwestern Development, 1800-1910," in Festschrift for Robert Gallman, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 130)
    - "U.S. Agriculture, 1800-1914," in Stanley Engerman and Robert Gallman, ed., Cambridge Economic History of the United States. With J. Fred Bateman, Jr. and Jeremy Atack, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 131)
    - "Business and Industry in the Twentieth Century," in R. W. Bulliet, ed., Columbia Economic History, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 132)
    - American Economic History, author unknown (Box 2, Folder 1)